A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Secretary and General Counsel, Grant Records, Organizational Grants FA1510
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Recommended Grant Action Forms and Affirmative Action Statements, 1
  - Telecommunications Cooperative Network, 1984 September (Box 5, Folder 194)
    To provide part of the capital to establish a shared voice network among nonprofit organizations to reduce long-distance telephone costs and increase use of computer communications techniques
  - Temporary State Commission of the Future of Postsecondary Education, 1976 November (Box 5, Folder 195)
    Partial support of survey of and planning for New York State higher education
  - Tenant Affairs Board (TAB), 1973-1980 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    1980 December - Terminal support to TAB for its teen parenting program
    1979 January - Terminal support for housing, employment, social service and education programs in conjunction with the tenant management of St. Louis public housing
    1979 January - Support for surrogate mother demonstration programs
    1975 April - Supplementary grant to extend the public housing tenant management demonstration in St. Louis
    1973 December - Supplementary grant to extend the public housing tenant management demonstration in St. Louis
    1976 May - Support for the St. Louis tenant management program and its employment, social services, video and education components
    1977 September - Partial support to assist the further development of housing, employment, social service and education programs in conjunction with the tenant management of St. Louis public housing
  - Earl Warren Legal Training Program, Inc., 1974 November (Box 5, Folder 197)
    Continued support for minority legal training program
  - Warren Wilson College, Inc., 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 198)
    Partial support of cooperative program involving a private college and a state university
  - Washburn Wire Products, Inc., 1980 November (Box 5, Folder 199)
    deferred - Loan to finance purchase of equipment
  - Washington Center for Learning Alternatives, 1981 June (Box 5, Folder 200)
    To increase undergraduate minority student participation in educational internships in Washington, D.C.
  - Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 201)
    1976 October (73-163) - Support for the Center's program of basic research on the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area
    1974 May - Supplemental funding to cover additional costs incurred by two grantees working under the Energy Policy Project
    1975 February - (73-163) - Support for the Center's program of basic research on the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area
  - The Washington Drama Society, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    To improve and stabilize the financial position
  - Washington International School, 1977 February (Box 5, Folder 203)
    Loan to help finance the purchase of property for new quarters for the School
  - Washington Journalism Center, 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 204)
    Support of a study to analyze the relationship between the media and the public in the U.S. by Marquis Childs and Richard Scammon
  - Washington Office of Latin America, 1983 September (Box 5, Folder 205)
    Support for human rights in Latin America
  - The Washington Research Project, Inc., 1976 July (Box 5, Folder 206)
    Partial general support for a national advocacy organization seeking to protect and enhance the rights of children.
  - State of Washington Department of Social and Health Services, 1974 June (Box 5, Folder 207)
    1) to provide support for planning supported work demonstration projects
    2) to provide increased support for research design and documentation of national supported work program
  - George Washington University - A.A., 1975-1984 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    1984 March - Support for the Center for Social Policy Studies of George Washington University for its evaluation of national social policies and programs
    1980 June - Support for the Center for Social Policy Studies of George Washington University for its evaluation of national social policies and programs
    1980 March - General support of the Office of Environmental Mediation
    1979 August - Research and training in reproductive sciences and contraceptive development
    1979 June - Support of a study of the feasibility of on-farm energy production (780-0499)
    1975 May - Support to the Office of Environmental Mediation to develop the process of environmental dispute mediation
    1976 August - Research and training in reproductive sciences and contraceptive development, Supplemental No. 1
    1979 October - Supplemental and terminal general support for the Institute for Educational Leadership, George Washington University
    1978 June - (#670-0578E) Further supplements to Grants #710-0158D and #670-0578E in general support of the Center for Social Policy Studies for its evaluations of national social policies and programs
    1978 January - Partial support for the Family Impact Seminar to test the substantive, administrative and political feasibility and desirability of family impact analysis
  - Washington University, St Louis, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    affirmative action statement
    1974 May - Support for the use of meditation in environmental dispute settlement
    1974 January - Support of Community Crisis Intervention Center
  - University of Washington, 1974-1986 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    Conditions Governing Access
    1986 May - to provide support for a challending and coherent alternative to the present general education curriculum
    1981 June - Support for Developmental and Outreach Activities of the Northwest Center for Research on Women
    1980 March - (1) Support for a competitive program of grants related to state environmental management (DAP 779-0814) (2) Five grants for state environmental management project supplements UW - Partial support for analysis of decentralized generation of electricity in Washington (supplement to 785-0148)
    1980 July - Computerization of catalog of East Asian serials collection
    1976 August - Support for advising education leaders on school instructional policies for gifted children
    1979 July - Start up project to evaluate the effectiveness of Indian Education Programs under the Indian Education Act of 1972
    1974 April - Additional support for doctoral students who are presently enrolled in Ford funded ecology training programs
    1975 August - Research on the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe - public ownership and management of resources in the Soviet Union
    1977 July - Partial support of the Office of the Environmental Mediation (Supplement No. 1, Grant No. 750-0379)
    1980 September - General support of the Institute for Environmental Mediation
  - Watts Labor Community Action Committee (WLCAC), 1975-1985 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    1985 September - Renewed support of central administration and project development
    1982 January - Continued support of central administration and project development
    1981 July - $500,000 line of credit to finance delayed payments in payroll and payroll-related expenses covered in existing public contracts
    1978 October - Guarantee of 50% of Bank Loan to Complete Housing Development in the Watts Area of Los Angeles
    1977 November - Continued support of central administration and project development
    1975 October - Continued support of central administration and project development
    1979 October - Continued support of central administration and project development
  - Wayne County Federated Library System (Michigan), 1975 May (Box 5, Folder 212)
    Purchase of films for regional Bicentennial film program
  - Wayne State University, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    1978 December - Partial support of the establishment of a Quality of Worklife Program for the State of Michigan
    1978 April - Partial support of research on the greater Detroit economy
  - Wellesley College, 1974-1986 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    1986 January - Supplementary support for projects to mainstream the new research on women into the core undergraduate curriculum of selected institutions across the country
    1983 August - Support for projects to mainstream the new research on women into the core undergraduate curriculum of selected institutions across the country
    1982 November - Support for the final two phases of two national child care projects
    1980 December - Support for the third and final phase of a national school-age child care project
    1980 May - Support for the second phase of a National School-Age Childcare Project
    Program for Affirmative Action
    1978 May - Support of Center for Research on Women
    1976 September - Supplementary Support of Regional Resource Centers for Women in Higher Education
    1974 June - Venture Fund grants to Northeastern instutions in support of innovations in undergraduate education
  - Westchester Residential Opportunities, 1983 December (Box 5, Folder 215)
    Program of assistance to minority home buyers
  - The University of Western Australia, 1984 September (Box 5, Folder 216)
    Support for a new research and training program in community epidemiology in Southeast Asian physicians
  - Western Center on Law and Poverty - WJH, 1978 September (Box 5, Folder 217)
    A study of inequities in state community college financing systems
  - Western Governor's Association, 1985 February (Box 5, Folder 218)
    Support for a water policy program
  - University of the West Indies, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    1985 June - (1) Support for a communications program at the Women and Development Unit; (2) Support for regional coordination of the Women and Development Studies Programme
    1985 May - Partial start-up support for a graduate program in applied social sciences
    1984 June - Partial support to establish an Office of University Services
    1983 June - Support for a program of research on women in the Eastern Caribbean
    1982 July - Support for a communications program at the Women and Development Unit and a modest staff development program
    1982 March - Support for applied research on child development
    1981 July - To support a Symposium on Women in Culture and a Regional Workshop on Methodologies of Popular Education
    1980 August - To develop and test an approach to integrating poor women into rural development programs
  - Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education (WICHE), 1976 April (Box 5, Folder 220)
    To help WICHE continue and expand its program of technical assistance to newly-established Indian colleges
  - The Western Network, 1984 June (Box 5, Folder 221)
    Support for Water Policy Dialogue Program to encourage participation of rural poor in dispute resolution and water policy decision-making
  - The University of Western Ontario, 1974-1985 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    1985 December - Support for Phase I of a research project on developing countries and the global trading system
    1981 April - Partial support of research on data protection in North American and Europe
    1974 August - Research on problems common to advanced industrial societies - Study of informational privacy and access to government microdata files for social science research
  - Western Organization of Resource Councils, 1984 May (Box 5, Folder 223)
    Policy research on natural resource ownership and management in Mountain states
  - Western Service Systems, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 224)
    1981 September - Partial supplemental terminal support of research and technical assistance regarding Colorado minority school finance problems
    1981 September - Support for program of dissemination of studies on Caribbean women
    1981 September - Support to establish a national information center on women and the military
    1979 November - Partial supplemental terminal support of research and technical assistance regarding Colorado minority school finance problems (780-0227)
    1978 February - Partial support of research and public information regarding school finance disparities for minority groups in Colorado
  - The University of the West Indies, 1985 December (Box 5, Folder 225)
    Support for applied research on child development, Supplement No. 1
  - West Los Angeles College, 1985 September (Box 5, Folder 226)
    Support to improve the college's institutional research capability
  - West Oak Lane Community, 1984 September (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - West Virginia University, 1980 March (Box 5, Folder 227)
    Partial support for analysisof the impact of increased energy production on state environmental management (Supplement to 786-0149)
  - WGBH Educational Foundation, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 228)
    WGBH - 1979 July - support for preproduction costs for a tv series on American labor history
    Watts Labor Community Action Committee - 1979 July - Loan to create a house moving organization to be owned by the Watts Labor Community Action Committee
    Columbia University - 1979 July - Partial support of a project on The Fountain of Aging to be conducted by Betty Friedan
    Cornell University 1979 July - Partial support for research on the "comparative ecology of human development"
    NOW Legal Defense and Education Fund - 1979 July - Partial support for a joint education and litigation project to interpret and implement state ERA's
    Women's Action Alliance - 1979 July - General support for programs that seek to eliminate sex description
    WGBH - 1978 October - Partial support of the documentary series "World" (previously read: To provide partial support of the documentary series "World"), Supplement No. 1
    WGBH - 1977 October - Partial support of the documentary series "World"
    WGBH - 1974 April - Support of public television programming activities in key production centers and PBS
    WGBH - 1976 February - Support of PBS TV coverage of League of Women Voters Education Fund '76 Presidential Forums
  - WHYY, Inc., 1979 April (Box 5, Folder 229)
    Loan to finance the relocation of Philadelphia's public television station to the Living History Center
    Employer Information Report
  - Wheaton College, 1985 January (Box 5, Folder 230)
    Support for faculty to mainstream new research on women and minorities into undergraduate curriculum at selected colleges
  - White House Fellows Foundation, 1976 January (Box 5, Folder 231)
    To help create a permanent endowment fund for the education and selection components of the White House Fellows Program
  - Wider Opportunities for Women, Inc., 1975-1984 (Box 5, Folder 232)
    1984 September - Partial support for the technical assistance, leadership, development, and monitoring activities of its Women's Work Force Network
    1975 July - For the evaluation of WOW's supported work program for women's offenders
  - Wilberforce University, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 233)
    1977 June - Fifth Grant to St. Augustine's College and Sixth Grant to Five Institutions all selected to participate in the Black College Program for Institutional Advancement
    1976 June - Fourth Grant to St. Augustine's College and Sixth Grant to Five Institutions all selected to participate in the Black College Program for Institutional Advancement
    1975 August - Third Grant to St. Augustine's College and Sixth Grant to Five Institutions all selected to participate in the Black College Program for Institutional Advancement
    1974 October - Second Grant to St. Augustine's College and Sixth Grant to Five Institutions all selected to participate in the Black College Program for Institutional Advancement
  - Wilgespruit Fellowship Centre, 1984 September (Box 5, Folder 234)
    Strengthening a network of community organizers assisting black self-help community groups, and funding seminars on the ideological bases of the liberation struggle
  - Winrock International Institute for Agricultural Development (WIIAD), 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 235)
    1986 January - Support to strengthen agricultural economics research and training in China
    1985 January - Support for a rural policy network in Africa
    1985 March - Support for the Institute's capital fund
  - Winston Salem State University, 1979 July (Box 6, Folder 236)
    The three projects, in different but related ways, would help public black colleges strengthen their plans for participating in the desegregation of higher education in the South
  - Wirtz and Lapointe, Inc., 1980 November (Box 6, Folder 237)
    Partial support of a review of the National Assessment of Educational Progress
  - Wisconsin Center for Public Policy - WJH, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    1980 January - Support for the Center's environmental mediation program (780-0546)
    1978 July - (1) Support for the Center's environmental mediation program; (2) Support of small grant actions and program development activities related to environmental conflict resolution
  - University of Wisconsin, 1974-1986 (Box 6, Folder 239)
    1985 September - Support for a conference comparing the causes and consequences of poverty for black Americans, Hispanics, and Native Americans
    1983 June - Partial support for an evaluation of Wisconsin's Child Support Assurance System
    1986 June - Comparative research on the impact of migration and settlement patterns on the economic well being of Puerto Ricans, Cubans and Mexicans in the United States
    1986 January - To monitor the second year of activity of Ford Foundation supported urban mathematics collaboratives
    1985 January - To monitor the first year of activity of Ford Foundation supported urban mathematics collaboratives
    1982 November - This series of grants would permit the establishment of five Hispanic Task Forces and a coordinative mechanism charged with developing policy research agendas in areas of concern to the Hispanic community
    1982 September - Support for integration of attention to women within development programs
    1979 June - Support for research and analysis of America's nonprofit sector
    1979 May - To implement Trustee approved program of postdoctoral study for underrepresented minorities
    1979 April - Support of Women's Studies Research Center
    1977 July - Partial support of faculty fellowship program in Wisconsin State environmental agencies
    1975 May - Training program in reproductive biology, Supplemental No. 2
    1974 December - Research on international economic order - an empirical approach to equilibrium and disequilibrium effects of international economic policy on efficiency, employment and distribution
    1975 May - Establishment of a Center for Development, Supplement No. 2
    1974 May - Support of a training program in university management, Supplement No. 4
    1974 September - Training program in development planning in Indonesia, Supplement No. 2
    1976 March - Training program in development planning in Indonesia, Supplement No. 3
    1976 December - Support for research on small urban centers in rural development
  - University of Witwatersrand (South Africa), 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 240)
    1986 June - Strengthening the law and freedom of expression programs of the University's Centre for Applied Legal Studies
    1984 August - Strengthening the labor law and freedom of expression programs of the University's Centre for Applied Legal Studies
    1982 September - Strengthening the labor law and freedom of expression programs of the University's Centre for Applied Legal Studies
  - The Woodlawn Organization, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 241)
    1979 July - Renewed support to enable TWO to retire accumulated deficits of $1,183,485
    1976 March - Continued support to enable TWO to continue its present programs in real estate, social services, and commercial activities
    1974 December - Loan to enable WCDC to undertake land banking phase of a major real estate redevelopment in Woodlawn community of Chicago
  - Women and Employment, Inc., 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 242)
    1986 March - Support for economic development and rural outreach of statewide women's employment organization in West Virginia, Supplement No. 3
    1984 March - Support for economic development and rural outreach of statewide women's employment organization in West Virginia
    1982 February - Support for economic development and rural outreach of statewide women's employment organization in West Virginia
  - Women Employed Institute, 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 243)
    1986 March - General support for its national, regional and local programs designed to improve the status and wages of working women
    1984 August - Partial support for a Joint Project of WLDF with Women Employed Institute to achieve improved enforcement of equal opportunity laws through monitoring, policy development and advocacy
    1982 July - Support for research to devise a model affirmative action program for clerical workers in the insurance industry
  - Women's Action Alliance, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 244)
    1975 November - Partial support of the Women's Action Alliance project to develop a National Women's Agenda and Coalition
    1974 June - Dissemination of results of program to eliminate sex role stereotyping in pre-school programs
    1977 June - Support for funding development project to expand support beyond foundation grants
  - Women's Documentation Center, 1985 January (Box 6, Folder 245)
    Support to establish a national documentation center on women
  - Women's Equity Action League (WEAL), 1976-1986 (Box 6, Folder 246)
    1986 April - Partial support of its program addressing sex equity in social security, private pensions, and insurance and a special one-time grant to deal with a cash flow problem
    1986 June - Partial support of their program addressing sex equity in social security, private pensions, and insurance
    1983 September - Continued support for their Project on Women and the Military
    1982 June - Continuing support of Intern Program
    1980 May - Continuing support of Intern Program
    1978 August - Supplementary support of Intern Program
    1976 July - Support of Volunteer-Intern Program
  - The Women's House of the Northeast (Brazil), 1982 August (Box 6, Folder 247)
    To support a rural women's handicraft cooperative and creche in Aldeia, Pernambuco
  - Women's Interart Center, 1976-1980 (Box 6, Folder 248)
    1980 April - Assistance toward stabilization of the Center's operations
    1978 June - Assistance toward stabilization of the Center's operations
    1977 October - Assistance toward stabilization of the Center's operations
    1976 May - Partial support for a public relations campaign to increase audiences and private contributions
    Affirmative Action Program
  - Women's Law Fund, Inc., 1974-1982 (Box 6, Folder 249)
    1982 September - General support for the Fund's litigation and public education efforts on behalf of women
    1980 August - Continued support for the work of the Fund in sex discrimination cases
    1978 July - Continued support for the work of the Fund in sex discrimination cases
    1976 June - Continued support for the work of the Fund in sex discrimination cases
    1974 May - Continued support for the work of the Fund in sex discrimination cases
  - Women's Law Project, 1974 December (Box 6, Folder 250)
    Support for research and publication in the equal rights amendment area
  - Women's Legal Defense Fund, 1978-1984 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    1984 August - Partial support for a Joint Project of WLDF with Women Employed Institute to achieve improved enforcement of equal opportunity laws through monitoring, policy development and advocacy (780-0398)
    1982 July - Partial support for a Joint Project of WLDF with Women Employed Institute to achieve improved enforcement of equal opportunity laws through monitoring, policy development and advocacy